Hi I am Mausam Kar. This is my
hybrid chemical equipment visualizer.
Let's jump straight in. I am logging into
the web app first. First I will
demonstrate the CSV upload by I am
selecting the required sample CSV. The
Jango back end parses this using pandas
and instantly returns the analytics. Here
are the. Visualizations using Chart JS.
As we can see, the visualizations are
the distribution by equipment type,
correlation between pressure and flow
rate, and temperature trends over time.
Here are the visualization. As we can
see, we also have a history management
saving the last five uploads for quick
access for each user. And also we
have a global log for all the user
uploads. We also have a dedicated feature
and guides page and a context section.
For now switching to the desktop
application built with Pyqt 5, I am
logging in with same credentials. Notice
how the data I just uploaded on the
web is immediately available here. This
proves the share back end. Integration
Instead of web charts, we are using
native matplotlib figures here for high
performance offline analysis. For
reporting I will just generate a PDF
report which is created server side with
report lab containing all the critical
statistics and equipment lists. Also we
can see the user information for. Each
user logged in into the website within
the dashboard for both web and the
desktop app. Here how it looks.
The entire stack is containerized using
Docker. My Docker compose setup
orchestrates this Django API, React front
end and database volumes as we can
see in our Docker desktop the images
that we have created for the front
end and back end services and also
the containers. On which both the
services are being running. Also we can
see the detailed log of the back end
requests sent to the front end. For back
end hosting we have used render. So this
is our render platform where we have
hosted the back end. For front end we
have used versal for deployment. This is
my versal dashboard where I have hosted
it. So as we can see, for
24/7 availability of the back end we have
used something called Uptime Robot. So
this is the Django administration panel
through which I can manage all the users
who are using my application.
The entire project is available in GitHub
and the documentation for the same is
being provided along with the preview
images for the application. The
architecture diagrams for both dockerized
and non dockerized development are being
provided in the README as well.